The Papers of Georg and Max Bredig
Science History Institute
- Series I: Georg Bredig Papers, I
  - Series I: Sub-Series I: Georg Bredig Correspondence File
    This sub-series primarily contains letters written to Georg Bredig, although several files include drafts and letter press copies of correspondence written by Georg Bredig. Files are arranged alphabetically by author. These files detail Georg Bredig's scientific activities before 1933 and include a large amount of correspondence from Svante Arrhenius, Jacobus van't Hoff, as well as Georg's son, Max Bredig.
    - Heidberg, Adolf - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 55
    - Planck, Max - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 36
    - Goldschmidt, Victor - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 48
    - Fuchs, R.F. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 43
    - Le Chatelier, Henry Louis - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 11
    - Rathke, Bernhard - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 40
    - Tromel, G. - Christmas cards, undated
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 58
    - Multiple Unidentified Correspondents - Correspondence/Letters (31 items)
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 27
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence to Walter Gebhardt
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 18
    - Meyer, K.H. - Correspondence/Postcards
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 19
    - Schwartzschild, Karl - Scientific paper about the solar spectrum
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 49
    - Ramsay, William - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 39
    - Ipatjev, W. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 5
    - Gebhardt, Walter - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 46
    - Friedlander, Paul - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 42
    - Rothmund, V. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 45
    - Peterson, Otto - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 35
    - Arrhenius, Svante - Correspondence (55 items)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 4
    - Wald, Frantisek (Franz) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 63
    - Niggli, Paul - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 31
    - Minister des Kultus, des Unterrichts und Badischer Finanz - und Wirtschaftsminister - Correspondence pertaining to Georg Bredig move to Holland
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 24
    - Bamberger, Eugen - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 6
    - Werner, A. - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 66
    - Hell, Carl Magnus von - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 56
    - Schär, Eduard - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 48
    - Duhem, Pierre - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 33
    - Billing, Herman - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 11
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence to unidentified recipients, 1922, 1928, 1938
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 20
    - Nernst, Walther - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 29
    - Hill, A. Croft - Correspondence, undated
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 58
    - Ruzek, Joseph - Christmas Cards, undated
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 47
    - Fraenkel, Rosa - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 38
    - Michaelis, Leonor - Correspondence/Postcards
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 21
    - Windaus, Adolf - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 69
    - Universum Book Export Co. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 60
    - Ehrlich, Paul - Correspondence, undated
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 35
    - Duisberg, Carl - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 34
    - Hoff, Jacobus, van't - Correspondence (28 items)
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 1
    - Multiple Unidentified Correspondents - Correspondence/Postcards (50 items)
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 28
    - Dimroth, Otto - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 31
    - Meyer, Hans Leopold - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 18
    - Ostwald, Grete - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 32
    - Höber, R. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 59
    - Haber, Fritz et. al. - Autographed postcard from attendees of a scientific congress in Kyoto, (includes autographs of Shinkichi Horiba)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 50
    - Eugler, Carl - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 36
    - Zweites Physikalisches Institut der Universitat - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 73
    - Sklarek, W. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 50
    - Quincke, Georg Hermann - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 38
    - Lottermoser, Alfred - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 16
    - Will, W. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 68
    - Zelinsky, Nikolay - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 71
    - Krieger, Marielle - Postcards and print of gate in Potsdam, undated
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 9
    - Neuberg, Carl - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 30
    - Findlay, Alexander - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 37
    - Horstamann, A. - Correspondence, 1915
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 4
    - Roth, W. A. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 44
    - Minister des Kultus, des Unterrichts - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 23
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence to J.H. van't Hoff
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 19
    - Haber, Fritz et. al. - Autographed postcard from attendees of a scientific congress in Vienna
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 51
    - Haber, Fritz et. al. - Autographed postcard from attendees of a scientific congress in the Netherlands, under the inscription, "Remembrances from Ostwald's Laboratory"
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 52
    - Anschütz, Richard - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 2
    - Ostwald, Wilhelm - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 33
    - Friedenthal, Hans - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 41
    - Svedberg, Theodor - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 55
    - Hempel, Walther - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 57
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Georg Bredig (78 items)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 22
    - Gatterman, Ludwig - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 45
    - Daniel Sieff Research Institute (Weizman Institute of Science) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 27
    - Lewis, Gilbert N. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 12
    - Bechhold, Heinrich - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 9
    - Homburger, Anna - Correspondence, undated
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 54
    - Bayer-I.G. Farben - Correspondence pertaining to "Torantil"
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 8
    - Bodenstein, Max - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 12
    - Department of State, American Consulate - Correspondence pertaining to immigration, together with statement of support from Ernst Cohen & H. R. Kruyt
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 29
    - Winkler, Clemens - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 70
    - Staudinger, Hermann - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 54
    - Miller, Oskar von - Correspondence/Postcards
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 22
    - Mittasch, Alwin - Holiday Card with mounted photograph of Mittasch, together with postcards
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 26
    - Lintner, C.J. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 13
    - Bunte, Hans - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 25
    - Deutsches Generalkonsulat–New York - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 30
    - Solvay, Ernest - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 51
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Georg Bredig (33 items)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 23
    - Hahn, Otto; Lisa Meitner and Theo Svedberg et. al. - Autographed postcard from attendees of the Mendeleev Congress, (includes autographs by Otto Hahn, Lisa Meitner, Theo Svedberg, et al.)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 53
    - Hoff, Jacobus, van't - Scientific notes sent to Georg Bredig (16 items)
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 2
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence to Otto Arrhenius
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 15
    - Roozeboom, Bakhuys - Correspondence, 1908
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 43
    - Kobert, Rudolph - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 6
    - Meyer, Richard - Correspondence/Postcards
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 20
    - Walden, Paul - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 64
    - Knietsch, Rudolph - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 8
    - Fraenkel, Walter - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 39
    - Goldschmidt, Heinrich J. - Correspondence, 1918
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 47
    - de Hevesy, George - Correspondence, 1929, 1927
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 28
    - Minister des Kultus, des Unterrichts und der Justiz - Correspondence pertaining to Georg Bredig's forced retirement, 25 October 1933
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 25
    - Bohr, Niels - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 13
    - Abegg, Richard - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 1
    - Franck, James - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 40
    - Reinders, W. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 41
    - Wegscheider, Rudolph - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 65
    - Lorenz, Richard - Signed, photograph portrait of Lorenz dedicated to Georg Bredig, undated
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 15
    - Vossler, Karl - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 61
    - Zsigmondy, Richard Adolph - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 72
    - Berl, Ernst - Correspondence, 1923
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 10
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence to Svante Arrhenius
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 16
    - Whitney, Willis R. - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 67
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence to W.L. Badger
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 17
    - Hollstein, Moritz - Correspondence with postcard of Glogau
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 3
    - Donnan, Frederick G. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 32
    - Ullman, Fritz - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 59
    - Reis, Alfred - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 42
    - Partington, J.R., et. al. - Autographed Postcard from multiple individuals attending scientific conference in London
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 34
    - Sommerfeld, Arnold - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 52
    - Price, Thomas Slater - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 37
    - Gabriel, Siegmund - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 44
    - Bredig, Georg - Drafts correspondence and notes pertaining to immigration to the United States (16 items)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 21
    - Waals, Johannes D. van der - Correspondence with notes related to van der Waals equations
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 62
    - Curtius, Theodor - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 26
    - Stark, T. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 53
    - Bunte, Earl - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 24
    - Bonhoeffer, Karl Friedrich - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 14
    - Bassett, H.L. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 7
    - Lunge, Georg - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 17
    - Arrhenius, Maria - Correspondence/Postcard, pertaining to the death of Svante Arrhenius
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 3
    - Kuhn, Richard - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 10
    - Traube, J. - Correspondence/Postcard
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 57
    - Tauss, S. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 56
    - Arrhenius, Svante - Correspondence/Postcards (28 items)
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 5
    - Koch, Robert - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 7
    - Haber, Fritz - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 1 folder 49
    - Rutherford, Ernest - Letter of recommendation for Kazimierz Fajans
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 46
    - Lobry van Troostenburg de Bruyn, Cornelis Adriaan - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 2 folder 14
  - Series I: Sub-Series III: Georg Bredig Oversized Items
    Items in Sub-Series III include oversized items such as diplomas, certificates, and newspapers.
    - Autographed etching of Fritz Haber
      Graphic Materials box 6 folder 4
    - Newspaper - Berliner Tageblatt. Includes article on Albert Einstein
      Text box 6 folder 3
    - Diploma of Georg Bredig - Doctor of Philosophy, University of Leipzig
      Mixed Materials box 6 folder 1
    - Newspaper - Munchner. Includes article on Albert Einstein
      Text box 6 folder 5
    - Certificates of Georg Bredig presented by the Grand Duke of Baden, and the Swiss Federal Council, 1911
      Mixed Materials box 6 folder 2
    - Newspaper - Illustrirte Zeitung. Includes cover image of Albert Einstein
      Text box 6 folder 6
- Series II: Max Bredig Papers, II
  Series II is comprised of the Papers of Max Bredig. It includes both a correspondence and subject file relating primarily to his efforts to help friends and family emigrate from Nazi occupied Europe.
  - Series II: Sub-Series I: Max Bredig Correspondence File
    This sub-series primarily contains letters written to Max Bredig, although several files include drafts and letter press copies of correspondence written by Max Bredig. Files are arranged alphabetically by author. These files primarily document Max Bredig's attempts to secure immigration visas for his family members and former colleagues so that they could leave war-torn Europe and join him in America. The sub-series also contains material related to Max's scientific activities and a large amount of correspondence with his father and sister.
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Correspondence (11 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 5
    - Israelitische Union E.V. - Organizational Literature & Acknowledgement of Donation
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 24
    - Multiple Correspondents - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding Max's application for U.S. citizenship (23 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 36
    - Urey, Harold (Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists) - (Max Bredig) - Appeals
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 18
    - Bredig, Max - Copies of outgoing Correspondence regarding the death of Georg Bredig
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 28
    - Wesseldy, P.J. - (Fritz Schnell) - Description of Alfred and Eva Schnell's life while in hiding in Holland, as told by a fellow "diver", 1945 August
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 24
    - Hildegard - Correspondence regarding the expulsion/deportation of Jews from Baden to the French Internment Camp in Gurs on October 21 & 22, 1940
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 15
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence and forms regarding Enemy Alien Registration and travel restrictions
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 27
    - Immigrant's Victory Council - Correspondence regarding receipt of registration and financial contribution
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 23
    - Keren Kajemeth Lejisrael - Correspondence/Organizational Literature and Acknowledgement of Gift
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 28
    - Askenasy, Paul - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 5
    - Russian War Relief, Inc. - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding acknowledgement of gift
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 7
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence/Testimony on behalf of Fritz Hochwald
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 25
    - Federation of American Scientists - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 6
    - USO War Fund/Greater NY USO - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence and Acknowledgement of Gift
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 19
    - Haber, Fritz - Correspondence (13 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 10
    - Schnell, Alfred and Eva - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence transmitted through the "Red Cross" from Holland (54 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 8
    - Halstead, Fridel G. - Correspondence (14 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 12
    - Unidentified Correspondents - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 16
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Hermann Mark - Draft
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 18
    - Raab, Friedrich - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding attempts to locate Georg Bredig
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 1
    - Loyalty Committee of Victims of Nazi-Fascist Oppression - Correspondence, newspaper clipping and membership card (Donation of P-40 Curtiss Warhawk Fighter Plane) - Loyalty
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 32
    - Hochwald, Fritz - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 17
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Paul Mangold and E. Terres regarding his unwillingness to participate in the celebration of the 50th anniversary of the Karlsruhe Chemical Society
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 32
    - Red Cross War Fund - (Max Bredig) - Acknowledgement of Gift
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 2
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence (48 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 12
    - Schnell, Frederico (Fritz) - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence Regarding Alfred and Eva Schnell. Includes photograph of Alfred and Eva with Eva's mother (26 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 9
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Correspondence regarding appointment of Max Bredig to a Fellowship in X-ray Crystal Structure at the University of Michigan (31 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 1
    - Vorstand der Judischen Gemeinde zu Berlin (Board of the Jewish Community) - (Max Bredig) - Organizational literature and acknowledgement of Gift, 1937
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 22
    - Hayn, Ilsa - Correspondence regarding Fritz Hochwald (13 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 13
    - Zielenziger, Kurt - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 26
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 11
    - Warburg, Otto - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 23
    - Van Der Sluys, Anny - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding Alfred and Eva Schnell
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 21
    - Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc. - (Max Bredig) - Appeal for Scientific Literature for Intellectuals cut-off from the scientific community in Nazi occupied France
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 12
    - Reis, Alfred - (Max Bredig) - Letters of Support to bring Reis to the U.S., (48 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 4
    - Multiple Correspondents - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding employment (16 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 35
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to K. Fajans - Drafts
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 22
    - Deutsches Konsulat - Correspondence regarding extension of Passport
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 37
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to the Society for the Protection of Science and Learning regarding the last days of Georg Bredig - Draft
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 31
    - Koppel, Max - Correspondence/Regarding Rudi Gutman (interned in Australia)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 30
    - Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc. - Organizational Literature
      Text box 9 folder 11
    - American Flying Services Foundation - Correspondence regarding appeals for donation
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 3
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence/Affidavits of Support for Viktor and Marianne's Immigration to the United States (71 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 19
    - Fajans, Kazimierz - Correspondence, (15 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 38
    - Boas, Fritz - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 7
    - Multiple Correspondents - (Max Bredig) - Letters of Condolence regarding death of Georg Bredig (includes Ernst Berl, Herman Mark, et al.) (47 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 37
    - Van Der Sluys, Anny - (Family of Alfred and Eva Schnell) - Mimeographed letters describing the life and death of the Schnells while hiding in Holland
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 20
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 8
    - H.G. Ollendorf, Inc. - Correspondence regarding shipment of Georg's library from Holland to the U.S. (14 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 9
    - Blackadder, T. - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 6
    - Taylor, Hugh S. - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding position for Georg at Princeton University (18 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 15
    - Bredig, Max - Drafts of outgoing correspondence (19 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 16
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence (47 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 15
    - Wolfsberg, Ilse - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence regarding help for her fiancée, Fritz Hochwald, who was interned at Miranda de Ebro Detention Camp, Spain (83 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 25
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence (97 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 13
    - Committee for Foreign Correspondence - Correspondence and Report
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 35
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence regarding support for his sister and father - Drafts (26 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 20
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Ernst Cohen regarding Georg's admission to the Netherlands
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 21
    - Mark, Herman - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence, 1938
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 34
    - Reichsvertretung der Deutschen Juden (Reich Representation of German Jews) - Appeal for Donation
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 3
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence/Application for Location Services for Alfred and Eva Schnell
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 29
    - Bredig, Georg - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 14
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence to Karl Boschwitz regarding Viktor Hamburger's arrest and imprisonment in Dachau - Drafts
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 17
    - Jaenicke, Johannes - Correspondence regarding Fritz Haber biography
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 26
    - American Association of European Chemists and Pharmacists - Bulletin
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 2
    - Bredig, Max - Correspondence/Draft Telegrams to and regarding Victor and Marianne Homburger (41 items)
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 24
    - Selfhelp of Emigres from Central Europe, Inc. - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence (15 items)
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 10
    - Jacoby, Gustav (Attorney) - Correspondence to the American Consulate et al. on behalf of Viktor and Marianne Homburger (36 items)
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 25
    - Antiaircraft Artillery Command - Eastern Defense Command - Correspondence regarding the loss and replacement of a set of binoculars
      Mixed Materials box 7 folder 4
    - Siebenmann, Charles - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence
      Mixed Materials box 9 folder 13
    - Neumann, Elisabeth - (Max Bredig) - Correspondence, regarding appeals to Max and Otto Loewi for assistance in securing release of her parents from Camp Pyrenees
      Mixed Materials box 8 folder 38
    - Kleiderkammer der Judischen Gemeinde - Correspondence/Acknowledgement of Gift